(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-22T17:09:56.762922",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
聞こえるか 聞こえるだろう
Can you hear it? Can you hear it?
はるかな 轟き
That distant roaring...
闇の中 心ゆさぶる
Shaking the heart in the darkness,
目覚め始まる
the awakening begins.
大地わり そそり立つ姿
Rising tall, splitting the earth—
正義の証か
is that proof of justice?
伝説の巨人の力
The legendary giant's power
銀河切り裂く
tears the galaxy apart.
雄叫びが電光石火の
A war cry like lightning-fast
一撃を呼べ
calling forth a single strike.
震えるな 瞳こらせよ
Don't tremble, fix your gaze—
復活の時
it is time for resurrection!
人よ生命よ 始まりをみる
Oh mankind, oh life, behold the beginning!
スペース・ランナウェイ イデオン イデオン
Space Runaway, Ideon, Ideon!
戦うか 戦えるか
Can you fight? Are you able to fight?
おびえる 心よ
Oh terrified heart...
迫りくる 悪の力に
Show your courage against
勇気を示せ
the encroaching forces of evil!
空に飛ぶ 輝く姿
Soaring into the sky, that radiant figure—
生命の叫びか
is it the cry of life itself?
伝説の巨人の力
The legendary giant's power
銀河切り裂く
tears the galaxy apart.
必殺の技が撃つのは
Is the finishing blow striking
我が身なのかと
against my very own body?
おそれるな 魂ひらけよ
Don't fear, open your soul—
復活の時
it is time for resurrection!
人よ生命よ 力をみる
Oh mankind, oh life, behold our power!
スペース・ランナウェイ イデオン イデオン
Space Runaway, Ideon, Ideon!
好き好き大好き
Like you, like you, I love you!
常識をはるかに超えてる想い
Feelings that far exceed common sense,
突然変異的に勃発したバラ色の恋
A rose-colored love that mutationally broke out.
もはや暴力とも言える程の純愛
A pure love so intense it could even be called violent.
既に昭和史に刻む勢いのジュ・テーム
A je t'aime with enough momentum to carve itself into Showa history.
Kiss me 殴るように唇に血が滲む程
Kiss me, so hard it draws blood on my lips as if beaten.
Hold me あばらが音を立てて折れる程
Hold me, until my ribs crack and break.
好き好き大好き 好き好き大好き 好き好き大好き
I love you so, so much...
愛してるって言わなきゃ殺す
If you don't say you love me, I'll kill you.
日常を打破して具体化するエロス
Eros that breaks through daily life to materialize.
本能で重ねる情事 無限地獄
An infinite hell of passionate affairs piled up by instinct.
アンチニヒリズムの直感認識は 潜在的幼児性暴力癖を誘発
The intuitive recognition of anti-nihilism induces latent infantile violent tendencies.
Kiss me 殴るように唇に血が滲む程
Kiss me, so hard it draws blood on my lips as if beaten.
Hold me あばらが音を立てて折れる程
Hold me, until my ribs crack and break.
好き好き大好き 好き好き大好き 好き好き大好き
I love you so, so much...
愛してるって言わなきゃ殺す
If you don't say you love me, I'll kill you.
Kiss me 殴るように唇に血が滲む程
Kiss me, so hard it draws blood on my lips as if beaten.
Hold me あばらが音を立てて折れる程
Hold me, until my ribs crack and break.
好き好き大好き 好き好き大好き 好き好き大好き
I love you so, so much...
いつでも グースカ ピー 星のカービィ
Always sleeping soundly, Kirby of the Stars.
けど 本当は 強い よ ホント かな
But is it really true that he's actually strong?
不思議な 力を もつ 伝説の ヒーロー
A legendary hero with mysterious powers.
強い 星の 戦士 やる もん だ カービィ
A strong star warrior, you go for it, Kirby!
平和な 楽園 誰かが 落とした 涙
In a peaceful paradise, tears someone dropped.
悪い 夢 なんか 食べて しまい ましょう
Let's eat up all those bad dreams!
なくした 笑顔を 取り戻しに 行く
We're going to reclaim our lost smiles.
空から 落ちてくる 星の 力を いっぱい 吸って
Inhaling all the power of the stars falling from the sky,
まんまる ピンク だよ 星の カービィ
A perfectly round pink ball, Kirby of the Stars!
けど なんでも なれる よ ホント かな
But can he really turn into anything?
無限の 力を もつ 伝説の ヒーロー
A legendary hero with limitless power.
強い 星の 戦士 たのん だよ カービィ
A strong star warrior, we're counting on you, Kirby!
いつも グーチョキ パー 星のカービィ
Always rock-paper-scissors, Kirby of the stars
けど 本当は 強い よ ホント かな
But he's actually strong, is that true?
不思議な 力を 持つ 伝説の ヒーロー
The legendary hero with strange powers
強い 星の 戦士 やる もん だ カービィ
Strong star warrior, way to go, Kirby!
平和な 楽園 誰かが 落とした 涙
In the peaceful paradise, someone dropped tears
悪い 夢 なんか 食べて しまいましょう
Let's eat up all those bad dreams
なくした 笑顔を 取り戻し に 行く ～ く ～
We're going to reclaim our lost smile...
空から 落ちて くる 星の 力を いっぱい 吸って
Inhaling the power of stars falling from the sky
まんまる ピンク だよ 星のカービィ
A perfect pink circle, Kirby of the stars
けど 何にでも なれる よ ホント かな
But he can become anything, can he really?
無限の 力を 持つ 伝説の ヒーロー
The legendary hero with unlimited power
強い 星の 戦士 たのん だ よ カービィ
Strong star warrior, we're counting on you, Kirby!
幸せ 楽園 なぜだか 邪魔が はいる よ
In this cheerful paradise, somehow disturbances appear
悩みの 種なら 食べて しまいましょう
Let's eat up all the seeds of worry
忘れた 気持ちを 取り戻し に 行く ～ く ～
We're going to recover the forgotten feeling...
はーい、ということでみんな来てくれてありがとう！コメント見てるよ！
Hii! So thank you everyone for coming! I'm reading the comments!
えー復活のイデアオン？好き好き大好き！でカービィマーチを
Eh, Ideaon's resurrection? I love it so much! So we sang Kirby ★ March
ちょっと…あれだね、3曲連続だとあれだね、息切れしちゃってすいません。カービィマーチを聞いてもらいました！ありがとうございます。
Wait... doing three songs in a row makes me breathless, sorry. You listened to Kirby ★ March! Thank you very much.
でね、今日のステージはこちら、あのダイナーがね、コンセプトとなっておりますので、コーンが途中で食べちゃったんだけどね、この細長いバーガーとかも結構こって作ってあるので、スクリーンをとってください！
And today's stage features this diner as its concept, so Korone ate part of it midway, but this long burger and everything is crafted in detail, so please take a screenshot!
でね、撮ってスクショは今日のハッシュタグは犬神ころね生誕祭2022でTwitterに投稿していただけるととっても嬉しいです！
And for taking screenshots, today's hashtag is #InugamiKoroneBirthday2022. I'd be super happy if you post them on Twitter!
でね、カービィマーチ1人で歌ったんだけど、やっぱりこれね、マーチは誰かと歌いたいなと思って、思いますが、誰かいたかな？あ、あの子なら多分一緒に歌ってくれると思うから、ちょっと行ってくるみんな、ちょっとこのままで待ってて、待っててね！
And, I sang Kirby ★ March alone, but you know, I think a march should be sung with someone, so I wonder if anyone's there? Ah, that girl will probably sing with me, so I'll go check, everyone, just wait right here, okay!
ケロッ！ケロッ！ケロッ！ いざ進め～っ
Kero! Kero! Kero! Advance now—
地球侵略せよ
Conquer the Earth!
ケッ ケロッ ケロッ 肩組んで 出かけた日にはいつも晴れ
Ke- Kero Kero, arm in arm, whenever we go out it's always sunny
「気をつけて～っ、目を食い縛れぇ！！！」
"Watch out—clench your eyes shut!!!"
カレーのライスを炊き忘れ 閉まるドア 小指はさんだ
Forgetting to cook rice for the curry, door closing, pinching my pinky
飛び乗ったら 行き先が違う 社員旅行はケロン
Jumping on the wrong train, the company trip is to Keron
あ、買った方が安いね 晩のおかずっ！！！
Ah, it's cheaper to buy it for tonight's side dish!!!
ピロッ！ピロッ！ピロッ！ 突撃は～っ 動く歩道で行け
Piro! Piro! Piro! Charge—Go on the moving walkway!
ピッピロピロ～っ 早寝して 寝坊して また二度寝する
Pippiropiro—Sleep early, sleep in, and go back to sleep
「全体～っ、止まれ 回れ お手っ！！！」
"Everyone—halt, turn, give a paw!!!"
嫌われたいの 愛されるいらないもの 買った大バーゲン
Wanting to be disliked yet loved, unnecessary things bought at a big bargain
ほしいものある とお金がない 四の五の言えよケロン
Wanting something but having no money, say what you will, Keron
あ、カミナリ鳴っても 隠すヘソがないっ！！！
Ah, even if thunder rumbles, there's no belly button to hide!!!
熱きこの血潮と 胸に刻まれし闘魂 永遠に勝ち誇れ 我らがケロン！
This hot lifeblood and fighting spirit engraved in our hearts, triumph forever, our Keron!
熱きこの血潮と 胸に刻まれし闘魂 永遠に勝ち誇れ 愛しき星よ！ 我らがケロン！
This hot lifeblood and fighting spirit engraved in our hearts, triumph forever, beloved star! Our Keron!
全体～っ、止まっちゃダメっ！ あぶ～～～……
Everyone—don't stop! Watch ou—...
ゲロッ！ゲロッ！ゲロッ！ 高らかに～っ 勝利のオタケビを
Gero! Gero! Gero! Loudly—The battle cry of victory!
ゲッツゲログゲロ～っ はりきって 電話に出たらファクシミリ
Getsugerogero—All pumped up, when I answered the phone, it was a fax machine!
“平成”は 本日 より “ケロロ元年”で ありまっす！！！
"Heisei" is starting today as "Keroro Year One"!!!
四角い トコロ は 丸く 掃け 水かき 汗かき ベタっかき
Sweep square places round, webbed feet, sweating, sticky sweating
歯みがき なら イチゴ の 香り ケロン は 宇宙一 たぶん
Strawberry scent for tooth brushing, Keron is number one in the universe, probably
あ 、 駅から 5分 は 実は 15分 っ ！ ！ ！
Ah, 5 minutes from the station is actually 15 minutes!
それ じゃー ソルジャー ど 疲れ さん っ ！ ！ ！
Well then, soldiers, great job!
ケロッとピッとワン
Kerotto, pitto, wan!
ケケロケロっと はりきって
Kekero-kerotto, getting fired up!
でんわして さんだん わくわく しみる
Make a call, make plans, so excited it tingles!
変性は本日よりケロの元年であります！
Starting today is Year One of Kero!
ちんかくいとくろ まあるく はて
Intriguing and dark, round and far,
みずかき おんせき てそく きっぺそくき
Webbed feet, hot springs, hand-foot-and-mouth,
はみだぎなら いちごのかおり
If it overflows, the scent of strawberries,
ケロは宇宙一いっぽん おふくろはちづはじゅうごふん
Kero is number one in the universe, Mom's map is 15 minutes!
そんじゃあ そんじゃあ おつかれさん
Well then, well then, good work!
ケロ ケロ ケロ ケロ ケロ
Kero kero kero kero kero!
こんばんは！ コロネ先輩！ 来てくれてありがとう！
Good evening! Korone-senpai! Thanks for coming!
こちらこそ呼んで…
Thanks for having me...
あれ？ 呼んでって言うか、これ今宵のさ、故郷じゃない？
Huh? Having you, or rather, isn't this tonight's hometown?
そうなんです！ なんの沙汰もなしにお越しいただきまして、ありがとうございます！
That's right! You came all the way here without notice, thank you!
あのね、めちゃめちゃ迷った！ 来るまでにめちゃめちゃ迷ったけどね、分かりづらかったですかね？
You know, I got so lost! I got so lost coming here, was it hard to find?
いや、めちゃめちゃ分かりづらかった！
Man, it was super hard to find!
来てくれてありがとうございます！ いや、でもないよ、せっかくね、故郷来ていただいたから…
Thanks for coming! Well, it's not like that—since you came all the way to my hometown...
そうだね。じゃ、記念撮影します！
That's right. Well then, let's take a commemorative photo!
え、じゃあみんなスクショ！ いっぱい撮ってね！ 撮ってください！
Eh, then everyone, screenshots! Take lots of pictures! Please take them!
何がいいかな、どんなポーズがいいかな？ あ、サバンナっぽく？ ゴースシ？
What should we do, what pose? Ah, like the savanna? Gōsushi?
ちょっと、ちょっとサバンナがリアルすぎて…
Wait, wait, the savanna is too realistic...
がおー！ がおー！ がおー！ がるるるる…
Gao! Gao! Gao! Grrr...
え,なになになに！ どうしたの？
Eh, what, what, what! What's wrong?
やばい！ このままだと、今宵、野生が戻っちゃうかもしれない！ やばい！ 逃げて！ 逃げて！ うわあー！
Oh no! If this keeps up, tonight my wild side might come back! Run! Run! Aah!
え、ごめん。倒しちまった。
Ah, sorry. I took her down.
あれ？ あれ？
Huh? Huh?
がおー…
Gao...
GO-GO たまごっち！
GO-GO Tamagotchi!
イエス・ノー たまご たまご たまごっち
Yes, no, tamago, tamago, Tamagotchi!
すなわちは友達 たまご たまご たまごっち
In other words, friends, tamago, tamago, Tamagotchi!
ピッタリパッチリ ペリマッチョ
Perfectly matching, peri-maccho!
たまご たまご たまごっち
Tamago, tamago, Tamagotchi!
毎日大吉 たまご たまご たまごっち
Great fortune every day, tamago, tamago, Tamagotchi!
毎日僕ら 星をまわすよ くるくる玉乗りみたい
Every day we spin the stars, like rolling a ball around!
毎日僕ら 夢を歌うよ 明日への手紙みたいだね
Every day we sing of dreams, like a letter to tomorrow!
凹んだ時こそ 凹んじゃいないこと 見つけるチャウチュウ
Especially when feeling down, finding things that aren't down, chau-chuu!
超ラッキー ラッキー 玉友友達
Super lucky, lucky, Tamagotchi friends!
イエス・ノー たまご たまご たまごっち
Yes, no, tamago, tamago, Tamagotchi!
すなわちは友達 たまご たまご たまごっち
In other words, friends, tamago, tamago, Tamagotchi!
ピッタリパッチリ ぺリマッチョ
Perfectly matching, peri-maccho!
たまご たまご たまごっち
Tamago, tamago, Tamagotchi!
毎日大吉 たまご たまご たまごっち
Great fortune every day, tamago, tamago, Tamagotchi!
それぞれみんな キャラが違うよ 関心するものキモいね
Everyone has a different character, fascinating and weird!
それぞれみんな 望み違うよ 欲しいものだっていいのいいのさ
Everyone has different wishes, whatever you want is totally fine!
だけど目を閉じて 手をつないだなら 連動キラリ
But if you close your eyes and hold hands, it syncs up sparkling!
超ハッピー ハッピー 優しさは同じ
Super happy, happy, kindness is the same!
イエス・ノー たまご たまご たまごっち
Yes, no, tamago, tamago, Tamagotchi!
すなわちは友達 たまご たまご たまごっち
In other words, friends, tamago, tamago, Tamagotchi!
ピッタリパッチリ 私
Perfectly matching, myself!
たまご たまご たまごっち
Tamago, tamago, Tamagotchi!
毎日大吉 たまご たまご たまごっち
Great fortune every day, tamago, tamago, Tamagotchi!
三日月がたの とくべつチケットに
Three-day moon is floating on a one-way ticket
金色 銀色 クレヨンで
With gold and silver crayons,
「ニャースのパーティ」ってかいえたなら
If it's called "Nyarth's Party",
気球にのって ばらまきのニャン
Ride the hot air balloon and scatter nyarth!
きんきんきらきら 夕陽がしずめば
Golden and sparkly, as the sunset sets in
それが パーティ はじまりの合図!
That is the party, the start signal!
銀河のジュータン しきつめた
Milky Way's juice box, packed tight
夜空の パーティ会場
Night sky's party venue
だれがくるかにゃ 誰もこないかにゃ?
Who is coming, nyarth? Nobody is coming, nyarth?
ドキドキしながら 待ってるにゃ
Waiting with a pounding heart, nyarth
(ニャン ニャン ニャースに 招待されたよ)
(Nyarth, Nyarth, invited to Nyarth's)
コーヒーカップも 無重力
Coffee cup is also zero gravity
(ニャン ニャン ニャースが うれしそうだよ)
(Nyarth, Nyarth, Nyarth looks so happy)
土星のわくで わなげして
Saturn's rings, make a funny face
(ニャン ニャン ニャースが なにかみつけた)
(Nyarth, Nyarth, Nyarth found something)
ソフトクリームの 星座だにゃ!
Soft serve ice cream constellation, nyarth!
「うまそうだにゃ~!」
"Looks so yummy, nyarth~!"
オーロラカーテン ゆらゆらと
Aurora curtain, swaying softly
かがやく パーティ会場
Glows at the party venue
お気楽スナック 光る フラッシュ!
Snack of fine instruments, shining flash!
にやにや笑顔に まぶしいニャ!
Grinning smiling face, dazzling nyarth!
(ニャン ニャン ニャースに 招待されたよ)
(Nyarth, Nyarth, invited to Nyarth's)
ギターにまたがり そらをとぶ
Straddling a guitar, flying through the sky
(ニャン ニャン ニャースが うれしそうだよ)
(Nyarth, Nyarth, Nyarth looks so happy)
ヨーヨーしながら さーれながら
Doing yo-yo, going around and around
(ニャン ニャン ニャースが なにかしてるよ)
(Nyarth, Nyarth, Nyarth is doing something)
時計のハリを 逆回し
Turning the clock hands backward
「時間よ止まれニャ~!」
"Time, stop, nyarth~!"
ダンダンスの リズム 変われば
Dancing rhythm changes,
そろそろ パーティ おしまい の合図!
Gradually, party ending signal!
やっぱり 時計は 動いてた
As expected, the clock was moving
眠そな パーティ会場
Sleepy party venue
もうすこしだけ あとちょっとだけ
Just a little more, just a little bit more
バイバイいうのは 待っててにゃ!
Saying goodbye? Wait for it, nyarth!
(ニャン ニャン ニャースに 招待されたよ)
(Nyarth, Nyarth, invited to Nyarth's)
ケーキに 星くず トッピング
Star dusting on top of the cake
(ニャン ニャン ニャースが うれしそうだよ)
(Nyarth, Nyarth, Nyarth looks so happy)
叩け ボンゴ 響け サンバ
Come play the bongos, come hear the samba
踊れ 南 の カルナバル
Dance to the rhythm of the carnival
誰も 彼も 浮かれ 騒ぎ
Let's party day and night until we feel alright
光る 汗 が はじけ とぶ
The sweat is shining, splashing as it flies
熱い 風 に 体 あずけ
I feel the hot breeze blow and let my body go
心 ゆくまで 踊れ ば
Until I'm in a trance
波 も 歌う よ 愛 の サンバ を
The waves sing my song, with samba, we belong
胸 に あふれる この リズム
The rhythm in my heart, we'll never be apart
オーレ オーレ マツケンサンバ
Olé, olé, Matsuken Samba
あぁ 恋せよ アミーゴ 踊ろう セニョリータ
Ah, fall in love, amigo, just dance, senorita
オーレ オーレ マツケンサンバ
Olé, olé, Matsuken Samba
あぁ 恋せよ アミーゴ 踊ろう セニョリータ
Ah, fall in love, amigo, just dance, senorita
眠りさえ忘れて 踊り明かそう
Forget about sleep and dance all night long,
サンバ ビバ サンバ
Samba, viva samba!
マ・ツ・ケ・ン・サンバ
Ma-tsu-ke-n samba!
オレ！
Olé!
叩け ボンゴ 響けサンバ 踊れ南のカルナバル
Beat the bongos, let the samba ring out, dance at the southern carnival.
夢のように 時は過ぎて はずむ南の恋の夜
Time passes like a dream on a lively southern night of love.
焼けた素肌 肩を抱いて 愛をささやき踊れば
Holding you close against my sun-kissed skin, whispering words of love as we dance.
白い渚に 恋も輝き 風に誘われ歌いだす
Romance shines on the white shore, invited by the wind as we begin to sing.
オーレオーレ マツケンサンバ
Olé, olé, Matsuken Samba!
あぁ 恋せよ アミーゴ 踊ろう セニョリータ
Ah, fall in love, amigo, let's dance, señorita!
眠りさえ忘れて 踊り明かそう
Forget about sleep and dance all night long,
サンバ ビバ サンバ
Samba, viva samba!
マ・ツ・ケ・ン・サンバ
Ma-tsu-ke-n samba!
オレ！
Olé!
いっしょにいられて幸せ
I'm happy when I can be with you,
しかられちゃうのも好き好き
and I really love it when you scold me too.
笑顔がないのもすてきよ
You're wonderful even when you don't smile,
私の願いをかなえて
please grant my wish!
しましょう しましょう しましょう はふーん
Let's do it, let's do it, let's do it, hafūn!
しましょう しましょう しましょう しましょう しましょう
Let's do it, let's do it, let's do it, let's do it!
初めてのあの日の鼓動
That first heartbeat from that day...
いつでも感じてたいの
I want to feel it forever.
どこまでもあなたと二人きりで
Anywhere, just the two of us alone,
何にでもときめきたいの
I want my heart to flutter at everything.
ねえ 恋した人って
Hey, anyone who's in love
誰でも魔法使いだよね
becomes a wizard, you know.
何げないことでもよろこべるのよ
Even the smallest things bring me joy.
いっしょにいられて幸せ
I'm happy when I can be with you,
しかられちゃうのも好き好き
and I really love it when you scold me too.
笑顔がないのもすてきよ
You're wonderful even when you don't smile,
私の願いをかなえて
please grant my wish!
しましょう しましょう しましょう はふーん
Let's do it, let's do it, let's do it, hafūn!
しましょう しましょう しましょう しましょう しましょう
Let's do it, let's do it, let's do it, let's do it!
初めてはひだまりの中
That first time in the warm sunshine,
優しく包んでくれたね
you gently wrapped me in your arms.
くちびるとくちびるが近づいて
As our lips drew closer together,
私は背伸びしたのに
even though I stood on my tiptoes,
どーしてあなた
why did you suddenly
いきなり逃げ出しちゃうの
run away like that?
どうしてあなた いきなり
Why did you suddenly...
逃げ出しちゃうのね
...run away like that?
私に振り向いてよ 夢の中でも
Turn around and look at me, even in my dreams.
一緒にいるのに なぜなぜ
We're together, so why, why is it
あなたは私を見ないの
that you won't look at me?
こんなにこんなに好きでも 願いは叶わないのね
Even though I love you this much, my wish won't come true.
嫌い 嫌い 嫌い 嘘だよ
I hate you, I hate you, I hate you—just kidding!
嫌い 嫌い 嫌い 嫌い 大嫌い
I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, I really hate you!
ねえ 大好きだよって 本当は
Hey, "I really love you," truth be told,
ささやきたいのね
I want to whisper to you.
いつの日か私たち 結ばれるよね
One day, we'll surely be bound together,
一緒にいられて幸せ
Being together is bliss,
叱られちゃうのも好き好き
Even getting scolded, I love it, love it,
笑顔がないのも素敵よ
Even when you have no smile, it's wonderful,
私の願いを叶えて
Please make my wish come true.
しましょ しましょ しましょ はほー
Let's do it, let's do it, let's do it, ha-hoo!
しましょ しましょ しましょ しましょ しましょ 初めてしましょ
Let's do it repeatedly, let's do it for the very first time!
はーい！ということで、マツケンサンバⅡと「初めてしましょ」聴いてもらいましたけれども、
Hi! So, you listened to "Matsuken Samba II" and "Hajimete Shimasho",
あのー、ころねすきが、なんとついに3Dのからすて……手で！待って！
Um, Koronesuki finally got a 3D... with hands! Wait!
あのね、前の、だいぶ前の歌枠でね、なんか「マツケンサンバⅡ一緒に3Dで歌おうね」みたいなに約束したの覚えてる、みんな？
You know, in a singing stream a long time ago, I promised like "Let's sing Matsuken Samba II together in 3D!", do you all remember?
それでね、今日、なんと約束が果たせました。
And today, somehow, that promise was fulfilled.
楽しかった？あ、楽しかったみたいだよ。
Was it fun? Ah, it seems it was fun.
せっかくだからちょっとね、撮影しようか！
Since we're at it, let's take a photo!
ちょっとみんなね、そっち向いてるんだよね、みんなね。
Everyone's facing that way, you see.
それじゃあね、まずね、ピースしよう、ピース！
Well then, first, let's do a peace sign, peace!
あ、撮れた？みんな。撮れた？
Ah, did you get it, everyone? Did you get it?
じゃあ、ちょっと、抱きしめてもらうかな？ころねすきに抱きしめてもらいます！あーーー！ちょっと、や、怪物みたいだねころねすきね、ちょっとね！
Then, shall we get a hug? Let's have Koronesuki hug me! Aaaaah! Wait, Koronesuki looks like a monster, haha!
ということで、えっと、次のね、曲もありますので、このころねすきにはね、前で見てもらおうかな。
So, um, we have the next song too, so let's have this Koronesuki watch from the front.
はい、一緒に踊ってくれてありがとう！ありがとうーー！
Yes, thank you for dancing together! Thank you so much!
ということで、ころねすきと一緒に歌った2曲でした！次の曲聴いてください。
So, those were the two songs I sang together with Koronesuki! Please listen to the next song.
このままいきます。
We'll go on just like this.
このまま歩き続けてる 今夜も回す
Continuing to walk just like this, spinning tonight as well.
一人の足あとたどって 果てしない
Tracing a single footprint, unending...
だけど君だけは どこかで待ってる
Yet you alone are waiting somewhere.
笑顔絶やさずに be the one
Without letting your smile fade, be the one.
be the one, be the one, alright!
明日の地球を投げ出さないから
Because I won't throw away tomorrow's Earth,
be the light, be the light, alright!
強くなれるよ 愛は負けない
I can become strong, love will not lose.
何かを助け救って抱きしめ
Helping, saving, and embracing something,
心に触れて届くよ 伝われ
Touching hearts, reaching you, let it be conveyed.
be the one, be the one, be the light
メッセージ送るよ 響くよ
Sending a message, it resonates.
何より大事な出来事 生きてる今夜も
More important than anything else, living tonight as well,
必ず前に進まなきゃいけない
We must surely move forward ahead.
昨日より強さと優しさ 大人になってる
Becoming more strong and gentle than yesterday, becoming adults.
みんな感じてる
Everyone is feeling it
ジャンプして
Jump up!
Be The One, Be The One, We Will
必ず夜明けは巡ってくるから
Surely dawn will come around again
Be The Light, Be The Light, We Will
未来へつなごう 過去をいたわろう
Let's connect to the future, cherish the past
現代を生きよう そしては忘れない
Let's live the present, and never forget
奇跡と偶然 太陽と月
Miracles and coincidence, sun and moon
Be The One, Be The Light
メッセージ届くよ 刻むよ
The message will reach you, I'll carve it in
You Will Be The One
Be The One, Be The One, We Will
make all your sight, You'll be the one
Be The Light, Be The Light, We'll take darkness into brightness yeah
Leading you into the light
Be The Light, Oh you will be alive
Be The One, Be The One, You will be the one
Be The One, We'll make a way!
フライングゲット
[Flying Get]
ギラギラ容赦ない太陽が
The blazing, merciless sun
強烈で照りつける on the beach
shines intensely on the beach
自惚れ温度は急上昇
Self-infatuation temperature rapidly rises
落ち着かないのは真夏の性だね
What keeps us unsettled is midsummer's nature
二人 目が合えば なぜか逸らすのに
When our eyes meet, we somehow look away
僕をまたすぐに見る
Yet you look right back at me again
君って…もしかして、もしかして…
Could you be... could it be...
フライングゲット 僕は一足先に
Flying Get, I'm a step ahead
君の気持ち今すぐ 手に入れようか
To claim your feelings right now!
フライングゲット 何か言われる前に
Flying Get, before anything is said
心の内ビビッと 感じるままに
Just feeling the spark deep inside
誰といて(誰といて) 微笑み方で(微笑み方で)
No matter who you're with, the way you smile
君が僕に恋を 恋をしているのは鉄板
It's certain you've fallen for me
フライングゲット だから誰より早く
Flying Get, so faster than anyone
君のハートの全て僕のモノ
I'll make your whole heart mine
好きだからラブ・フラゲ!
Because I love you, Love Furage!
クラクラ動揺した純情で
With a dizzy, shaken pure heart
砂浜チラ見してたビキニ
You peeked at the bikini on the sand
告白ウェルカムさ おいでよ
A confession is welcome, come on over
素直にならなくちゃ 楽しくないって
You have to be honest or it's not fun
その目、誘ってる 僕に来てくれと
Those eyes are inviting me to come to you
それが妄想としても
Even if that's just my delusion
声をかけてみなくちゃ始まらない
You can't start without speaking up
フライングゲット 君に空振りしても
Flying Get, even if I strike out with you
当たって砕けりゃ男じゃないか
Isn't it manly to swing and miss?
フライングゲット いつもやるだけやるさ
Flying Get, I'll always give it my all
黙って見てても恋はできないよ
You can't fall in love just watching silently
勇気足して(勇気足して) 一番乗りで(一番乗りで)
With added courage, being the very first
僕が君にゾッコン ゾッコン何度も見そう
I'm head over heels for you, time and again
フライングゲット 予約を待ってるような
Flying Get, like waiting for a reservation
周りの男達を出し抜いて
Outsmarting all the surrounding guys
得意げにラブ・フラゲ!
Smugly, Love Furage!
フライングゲット 僕は一足先に
Flying Get, I'm a step ahead
君の気持ち今すぐ 手に入れようか
To claim your feelings right now!
フライングゲット 何か言われる前に
Flying Get, before anything is said
心の内ビビッと 感じるままに
Just feeling the spark deep inside
誰といて(誰といて) 微笑み方で(微笑み方で)
No matter who you're with, the way you smile
君が僕に恋を 恋をしているのは鉄板
It's certain you've fallen for me
フライングゲット だから誰より早く
Flying Get, so faster than anyone
君のハートの全て僕のモノ
I'll make your whole heart mine
好きだからラブ・フラゲ!
Because I love you, Love Furage!
暮れなずむ夕日を背にして
With the fading sunset at our backs
もっとそっとしていても声を
Even if we stay a bit closer and quiet
かけてみなきゃ始まらない
We can't begin without speaking up
フライングゲット 君に空振りしても
Flying Get, even if I strike out with you
当たって砕けろ あの男じゃないか
Isn't it time to swing and miss?
フライングゲット いつもやりたいやるさ
Flying Get, always doing what I want to do
黙ってみてても声は売り決めるよ
Even if you watch silently, you decide your voice
フライングゲット ようやく待ってるような
Flying Get, like finally waiting
周りの男たちを出し抜いて
Outsmarting all the surrounding guys
得意げにラブ・フラゲ!
Smugly, Love Furage!
フライングゲット 僕は一足先に
Flying Get, I'm a step ahead
君の気持ち今すぐ 手に入れようか
To claim your feelings right now!
フライングゲット 何か言われる前に
Flying Get, before anything is said
ギラギラ容赦ない太陽が強烈に照りつける on the beach
The dazzling, relentless sun shines hot on the beach
自惚れ温度は急上昇 落ち着かないのは真夏の性だね
My vanity temperature is skyrocketing, what makes me so restless is my midsummer nature
二人 目が合えば なぜか逸らすのに 僕をまたすぐ見る
Whenever our eyes meet, why do you look away yet immediately look at me again?
君って… もしかして、もしかして…
Could it be, could it be...
フライングゲット 僕は一足先に
Flying Get, I'll take the lead
君の気持ち今すぐ 手に入れようか
And get my hands on your feelings right now
フライングゲット 何か言われる前に
Flying Get, before you say anything
心の内ビビッと 感じるままに
I'll feel the beat of your heart just as it is
誰といても 微笑み方で
No matter who you are with, with that smile
君が僕に恋を 恋をしているのは鉄板
It's a given that you've fallen in love with me
フライングゲット だから誰より早く
Flying Get, so faster than anyone else
君のハートの全て 僕のモノ
All of your heart will be mine
好きだからラヴ・フラゲ!
Because I like you, love frag!
クラクラ動揺した情趣で 砂浜チラ見してたビキニ
Dizzy with shaken innocence, I glanced at the bikinis on the sandy beach
告白ウェルカムさ おいでよ 素直にならなくちゃ 楽しくないさ
Confession welcome, come on, if you don't be honest, it's not fun
その目、誘ってる 僕に来てくれと それが妄想としても 声をかけてみなきゃ 始まらない
That look in your eyes invites me to come to you, even if that's just a delusion, if you don't call out, nothing begins
聞いてくれてありがとう!
Thank you for listening!
まあね、言いたいことはあるよね？
Well, you have things you want to say, right?
え？
Eh?
え、コロネおめでとうじゃないの？言いたいこと。
Eh, isn't it "Korone, congratulations"?
あの、さい、最初と最後のさ、あの、「ふーっ」ってやつね！
Um, at the very beginning and the end, that "Whew!" part!
なんでね！なんで歌うんだよ！なんでだよ！やっと交代よ！
Why! Why are you singing it! Why! It's finally our turn!
ま、でもノエルが言ってるから、ノエルに任しとくかって。
Well, but Noel said so, so we left it to Noel.
なるほどね、あそこなんかさ、見せば見せば、え、こんなのないよ！
I see, and that part, like, show it off, hey, there's no such thing!
いや、素敵なプレゼントもあったよ！あ、そうだよ！プレゼント！そう、お誕生日！おめでとう！
We got wonderful presents too! Ah, that's right! Presents! That's right, happy birthday! Congratulations!
せっかくだからね、あの、みんなと写真を撮りたいなと思って、終わりたい！
Since we're at it, we wanted to take a picture with everyone and wrap it up!
え、いい、いい、真ん中で、真ん中でね！よかった、あ、そんな真ん中だよ！ありがとう！ありがとう！
Okay, okay, in the middle! Great, oh, right in the middle! Thank you! Thank you!
はい、はい、なんでこの急にシュールって何だよ！
Yes, yes, why suddenly surreal, what's that!
え、なんか他にしたいことないんですか？ え、ここやっぱりさ、このさ、砂浜満喫よ、砂浜満喫！
Eh, isn't there anything else you want to do? Here, as expected, enjoying the sandy beach!
そう、なんかね、あの「あはは、待って」みたいな！あははは、なるほどね、追いかけっこしたいなと、思って。
Yeah, like, "Ahaha, wait!" I see, we wanted to play tag.
なんか、あ、なんか、ちょうどここここ、枝なんて使おう。
Like, oh, there's a branch right here, let's use it.
いいね、いい感じ。よしじゃあここね、いくぞ、持ってこい！
Nice, feels good. Okay, let's go here, bring it!
それじゃあ！
See ya!
ああ、みんな帰ってしまった。ちょっとね、あのコーンはこのあと、普通のね、あの、お洋服に着替えてくるんだけど、その前にちょっとあの、すごいやりたかったことがあって、その動画をね、運営さんがすごく頑張って作ってくれたのがあるないので、それをみんなちょっと見てて待っててください。ちょっとお着替えしてくるから、見てて待っててね！待っててね！
Ah, everyone's gone home. Before I change into my normal clothes, there's something I really wanted to do, and management worked super hard to make a video for it, so please wait and watch it! I'll go change, so wait and watch!
恋のカーニバル招待状が届いたよ
An invitation to the carnival of love has arrived
ポニピュッピュッピュッ トゥンピークンピー パンポピンポッ トゥンピークンピー
Poni-pyu-pyu-pyu, tumpy-kumpy, panpo-pinpo, tumpy-kumpy
ミミズさんがお出迎え
Mr. Earthworm welcomes you
気持ち悪い
Gross
ポニピュッピュッピュッ トゥンピークンピー パンポピンポッ トゥンピークンピー
Poni-pyu-pyu-pyu, tumpy-kumpy, panpo-pinpo, tumpy-kumpy
きれいなシャンデリア
A beautiful chandelier
タコさんウインナー食べ放題
All-you-can-eat octopus wieners
爪楊枝は刺さってますか？
Are the toothpicks stuck in?
ダンゴムシは放し飼い
Pill bugs are free-range
踏みつぶしますよ
I'll crush them
ああ ジャーマネほしい 立候補しますよ～
Ah, I want a manager! I'll run for candidate~
チョコレートのケーキを食べたの
I ate a chocolate cake
お腹の中が トリトントント タンタントンティントン
Inside my stomach, tori-ton-ton-ton, tan-tan-ton-tin-ton
イチゴのショートケーキを食べたの お腹の中が
I ate a strawberry shortcake, inside my stomach...
トリトントント タンタントンティントン
tori-ton-ton-ton, tan-tan-ton-tin-ton
トリトントントで わけわからんボルギーニ
Tori-ton-ton-ton, and some incomprehensible Bolghini
フフフフン！
Fufufu-fun!
言わせて頂いますが
If I may say so...
きますが 今年で36歳
though it's coming up, at 36 this year,
あとがないですよ〜
we're running out of time~!
挑戦し続ける姿は まさに三つ編みのジャンヌダルクですね
Her appearance of continuing to challenge is truly Joan of Arc with braids.
光のさす方へ 走り続け
Continuing to run toward where the light shines
時には立ち止まってもいいさ
It's fine to stop and rest at times
君は一人じゃない
You're not alone
共に手を取り合い さぁゴールしよう
Let's hold hands together and reach the goal
急なんですか！
What's with the sudden song?!
チョコレートのケーキを食べたの お腹の中が
I ate a chocolate cake, and inside my stomach...
トリトントン タンダンティントン
Tritonton tandantinton...
イチゴのショートケーキを食べたの お腹の中が
I ate a strawberry shortcake, and inside my stomach...
トリトントン タンダンティントン
Tritonton tandantinton...
トリトントンってわけわからんボルギーニ！
Tritonton means what the heck is a Borgini!
フフフファン！
Fufufufun!
はい、着替えてきましたー！
Alright, I've changed my clothes!
ということでね、あのみんなもう察してると思うけど 誕生日グッズ出てます！こちら、ドーン！
So everyone probably already figured it out, but birthday goods are out! Here they are, ta-da!
はーいどうも！お知らせ担当のコーナーでございます。
Hello everyone! It's Korone in charge of announcements.
今回も誕生日記念グッズ出るぞ！パフパフドンドン！
Birthday commemorative goods are coming out this time too! Fanfare drumroll!
今回の生誕祭ライブはですね、ダイナーをコンセプトにしておりまして、それに合わせて誕生日グッズもダイナー仕様となっております。
This birthday live stream has a diner concept, and to match that, the birthday goods are also diner-themed.
一つずつ紹介していきますね。まずは、こちら！
I'll introduce them one by one. First, this one!
ダイナー風B2タペストリー！この可愛いコーナーはフカヒレママに描いてもらったよ。
Diner-style B2 tapestry! This cute Korone was drawn by Fukahire-mama.
気づいた方もいると思うんですけれども、コーナーのね、オリ曲の「ドギーゴッツストリート」の衣装を着てます。
I think some people might have noticed, she's wearing the outfit from Korone's original song 'Doggy God's Street'.
なので、ダイナーの店員さんとして働いてる時のコーナーかなと思います。可愛いですね。
So I think it's Korone working as a diner clerk. It's so cute.
続いてこちら！フトイヌ＆ホソイヌグラス！
Moving on to this! Futo-inu & Hoso-inu glasses!
こちらはね、コーナーがなんと描き下ろしをしました。まあ描き下ろしたって言っても、線をね2、3本書いただけなんですけれけれども、ちゃんとね、あのフトイヌの方は線が太かったり、ホソイヌは線が細かったりとかして、こだわりを感じる一品でございますね。
For these, Korone actually did illustrations, just a few lines, but Futo-inu has thicker lines and Hoso-inu has thinner ones!
続いてこちら！ころねの部屋着風アロハシャツ！
Moving on to this! Korone's loungewear-style aloha shirt!
ころねの部屋着めちゃ可愛いいよね。外用の服も欲しくない？ってことで作りました。来年の夏はこれで決まりだね！黄色地に白い模様なので、がっつり目立つ感じでもないよね。なので着やすいかなと思いますので、お外でたくさん着て欲しいなと思います。
Korone's loungewear is super cute. We made this so you can wear it outside too. Next summer is decided with this!
続いてはこれ！Doggyプレート！ こちらはね、ドギーゴッツストリートのMVのコーナーのお皿となっております。
Next is this! Doggy Plate! This is Korone's plate from the MV of 'Doggy God's Street'.
そしてそして、今回全部セットをご購入していただいた方には、ダイナーで働くコーナーのボイスと直筆サインがみんなについてきます。数量限定ではなくご購入いただいた方全員にサインを書きますので、ご購入に急がなくても大丈夫でございますので、よろしくお願いいたします。
Those who purchase the complete set this time will get Korone's voice as a diner worker and a handwritten signature!
一つ一つ運営さんたちと考え作ったので、ぜひお手にとってもらえたらと思います。以上お知らせ担当のコーナーでしたー！
We thought about and made each one with the management, so I really hope you can pick them up. That was Korone!
よかったらぜひぜひご検討のほどお願いします。
If you'd like, please consider it.
あとこのあとすぐですね、あのメンバーシップ限定で、2次会みたいなやつのね、なんかあの歌を2曲ぐらい歌いますので、そちらも楽しみにしていただけたらと思います。
Also right after this, for membership limited, like an after-party, I'll sing about two songs, so I hope you look forward to that as well.
ということでもう寂しいね、次が最後の曲となってしまいました！皆さん今日は来てくれてありがとうございます。
So it's already lonely, the next song will be the final one! Thank you everyone for coming today.
ちょっとね、コーナーあの頭につけるものがあるのでちょっとみんなそこで待っててください。すぐね、すぐ始まりますので。
Wait a minute, Korone has something to put on her head, so everyone please wait there for a moment. It'll start right away.
あ、なんか、あれ？なんかなんかVTRがあるみたいなんですけど、え？今、今やってていいんですか？あ、じゃあVTRどうぞ！
Ah, it seems like there's a VTR, eh? Can I keep doing it right now? Ah, then VTR, go ahead!
皆さんこんにちは、ソニックチームです！
Hello everyone, we are the Sonic Team!
去年にと引き続き今年もコメントをさせていただきました！
Following last year, we also gave a comment this year!
今年はソニックイヤーでころねさんとのコラボも大きく賑わってますね！
This year is Sonic Year, and the collaboration with Korone-san is also very lively!
改めてまして、お誕生日おめでとうございます！これからも頑張ってください！
Once again, Happy Birthday! Please keep doing your best!
さあそして今年も彼からメッセージがあるみたいなのでご覧ください。
And now, it seems there's a message from him this year too, please take a look.
え？なんと今年はあのキャラからも…？
Eh? Could it be that this year even that character...?
なんと今年はあのキャラからも…？
Could it be... even from that character this year?
それではVTRどうぞ！
Now, roll the VTR!
Happy Birthday ころね！
Happy Birthday, Korone!
元気にやってるか？
How's it going?
俺はソニック、ソニック・ザ・ヘッジホッグだ！
I'm Sonic, Sonic the Hedgehog!
で、一緒に来てくれたこいつが…ナックルズ！
And the guy who came with me is... Knuckles!
ナックルズ・ザ・エキドゥナだ！
Knuckles the Echidna!
まぁ、お前はゲームプレイで俺をかっこよく見せてくれたらしいし、ソニステの借りもあるしな。
Well, you made me look cool in your gameplay, and we've got the Sonic Station debt to settle too.
だから、まぁ、おめでとさん！
So, uh, congratulations!
タク、普通にお祝いを言えばいいのに、ナックルズはまわりくどいぜ。
Geez, he could just say happy birthday normally. Knuckles is so roundabout.
相変わらずすごい人気だな！今も長い時間配信頑張ってるのか？
You're as popular as ever! Still working hard on those long streams?
俺なんか同じ場所に１０分と居られないから、お前って、ほんとにすごいと思うぜ！
I can't stay in one place for even 10 minutes, so I really think you're amazing!
でもあんまり無理はするなよ。気合と根性にしたって、それはよく寝た頭からわいてくるもんだからな。
But don't push yourself too hard. Even drive and grit come from a well-rested brain, you know.
今度会ったとき、青い顔してやがったらぶっとばすぞ！
Next time we meet, if you're looking pale, I'll beat you up!
Hey Knuckles! 素直に体に気を付けて頑張ってって言えばよくな。
Hey Knuckles! You could just honestly say "take care of yourself and do your best."
ってなわけで、俺たちからお前に誕生日のお祝いメッセージだ☆
That being said, this is our birthday congratulatory message to you☆
これからも応援よろしくな！See You～ またな！
Keep supporting us from now on! See you~ Later!
えーーー！うそ、うそ、うそ！
Eeeh?! No way, no way, no way!
え、ソニック、ソニックチームの皆さん、とソニックとナックルズだって、ありがとうございます！
Eh, Sonic, everyone on the Sonic Team, Sonic and Knuckles too?! Thank you so much!
あのね、ソニックチームのみなさんみんな優しくってね、本当大好きです！あのこれからも、あの、お世話になり、なると思うので、え、めっちゃ嬉しい！え、めっちゃ嬉しい！
You know, everyone on the Sonic Team is so kind, I really love them! Um, I think I'll be in their care from now on too, so... ah, I'm so happy! Ah, I'm so happy!
え、ちゃんと歌えるかな？ありがとうございました！
Eh, can I even sing properly now? Thank you very much!
え、なんかもう1本あるらしい。え、誰？あ、じゃあもう1本あるみたいなので、おねがいします、どうぞ！
Eh, it seems there's another one. Eh, who? Ah, well, it looks like there's another, please go ahead!
レベルファイブの日野です。え、ころねさん、10月1日は誕生日ということでおめでとうございます！
I'm Hino from Level-5. Uh, Korone-san, since October 1st is your birthday, congratulations!
え、こないだやらせてもらったコラボもですね、僕ら大変あの、いい結果を出しておりまして、え、喜んでおります。スタッフ一同。
The collaboration we did recently also produced some great results for us, and, uh, all the staff are delighted.
これからもですね、あの、もう、あの、仲良くさせていただきたいと思いますので、レベルファイブ共々よろしくお願いします！本当におめでとうございます！
We hope to continue getting along well with you, so please support Level-5 as well! Huge congratulations!
日野社長！え、本物？うれしすぎ！ありがとうございます！
President Hino! Eh, the real one? I'm so happy! Thank you so much!
えーと、妖怪ウォッチ大好きです。あ、妖怪ウォッチ以外も大好きです。ありがとうございます！
Um, I love Yo-kai Watch. Ah, I love things other than Yo-kai Watch too. Thank you so much!
あーうれしい、ちょっともう言葉が出てきません。あの、もう歌えないかもしれない。
Ah, I'm so happy, I'm out of words. Um, I might not even be able to sing anymore.
ということで、じゃあ、え、待って？え、え、もう1本ある、もう1本あるみたいです。ちょっと待って、まだ、ちょっと紹介しきれてないそのソニックチームと日野社長と、え、じゃあ、あの、お願いします、どうぞ！
So, well, eh, wait? Eh, eh, there's another one, it seems there's another one. Wait, I haven't quite finished introducing the Sonic Team, President Hino, and... um, well, please go ahead, go ahead!
はじめまして。ドラゴンクエストゲームデザイナーの堀井雄二です。
Nice to meet you. I'm Yuji Horii, game designer for Dragon Quest.
犬神ころねさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Inugami Korone-san, happy birthday!
ころねさんはDQが好きとのことで、プレイしていただきとても嬉しく思っています。
I heard you like DQ, Korone-san, and we're very happy you've been playing it.
ころねさんのDQⅢのゲーム配信は見させていただきましたよ。
I watched your DQIII game streams, you know.
ゲーム内の性格診断テストで、「西に進むべし」と看板に書かれているところで、西は右側だと思って右に行ったら、落とし穴に落ちてしまいましたね。（西は右側が正解）その結果、勇者ころねの性格診断が「わがまま」になってしまいました。その節は大大変失礼いたしました。（もしかして当たっていました？）
In the in-game personality test, where a sign said "Proceed West," you thought west was on the right and went right, falling into a pit trap. (West was actually on the left). As a result, Hero Korone's personality diagnosis became "Selfish." I offer my sincere apologies for that incident. (Was it perhaps spot on?)
他にも洞窟の宝箱でミミックの罠にハマったり、モンスター格闘場で高倍率を当てたりととても楽しい配信をありがとうございます。
Also getting caught in Mimic traps in cave chests, hitting high odds at the monster arena, thank you for such entertaining streams.
DQシリーズはこれまでたくさん出ておりますので、また別のシリーズも遊んでいただきたいですし、
There are many DQ series games out so far, so we'd love for you to play other titles as well,
DQXオフラインや、12月に発売するDQトレジャーズ、その先にも色々開発していますので是非遊んでくださいね！
and please play DQX Offline, DQ Treasures releasing in December, and we have various things in development beyond that too!
ところで、ころねさんが初めて遊んだDQはⅥと聞きました。なんとここに1995年に発売されたスーパーファミコン版のDQⅥの新品ゲームがあります。
By the way, I heard the first DQ you ever played was VI. Well, here I have a brand-new copy of the Super Famicom version of DQVI released in 1995.
これをプレゼントしたいと思います。
I'd like to present this to you.
堀井さん、それに堀井さんのサインをころねさんあてに書いていただくことってできますかね？
Horii-san, would it be possible to have you write your autograph addressed to Korone-san on it?
いいですよ。じゃあ書きましょうか。はい。
Sure thing. Shall I write it? Okay.
やった！ころねさん、やりましたよ！じゃあこれ、はいはい。緊張しますね。
Yay! Korone-san, we did it! Then here, right here. This is nerve-wracking.
え、嘘でしょ！？
Wait, no way?!
触ってるじゃん！
You're touching it!
ほ、堀井さんのスライム！
Th-That's Yuji Horii's slime!
あはははは！すごい！
Ahahaha! That's amazing!
サインとか入れたほうがいいですもんね。
You should probably sign it and stuff.
じゃあ、2022年10月1日。
Let's see, October 1st, 2022.
はい。10月1日。はい。
Right, October 1st. Right.
これでいいです。
There, all done.
これからも笑顔いっぱいの楽しい配信を楽しみにしてます。
I look forward to your many more smiling, fun streams.
それでは、ゆびゆび～♪
Now then, yubi yubi!
うわぁ！
Whoa!
うわぁ！すごーい！今、本当に触ったの持ってる！本物だよ！すごっ！
Whoa, amazing! You're holding what he actually touched! It's the real deal! So cool!
え、これ堀井さんが触ったやつですか？
Wait, is this what Yuji Horii touched?
あの、殿堂空間にあります、この。すっごい！え、持って！
Um, it's in the Hall of Fame space, this. So amazing! Hold it!
え、しかも、なんか、え、あれ、運営さん、え、ありがとうございます。え、あの見えてないと思うけど、これ持っ...え、嬉しい！
Wait, and also management, thank you so much! Um, you probably can't see it, but I'm holding... Yay!
あの、え、ちょっと待って、あの、快作に話しかけてたのは運営さんですか？あの堀、堀井さんに？
Um, wait a second, was that management talking to... Yuji Horii?
え、だ、誰ですか？え？スクウェア・エニックス、ドラゴンクエストシリーズチーフプロデューサー、三宅さん！え、待って、どっちもすごい方だったんですけど！
Wait, who? Square Enix DQ Chief Producer, Miyake-san! Wait, they're both such incredible people!
えっと、堀井さん、三宅さん、ありがとうございます。そして、運営さん、え、ありがとうございます。
Yuji Horii-san, Miyake-san, thank you very much! And management, thank you so much!
サプライズ！嬉しい。ちょっと待って、歌えないかもしれないです。
A surprise! I'm so happy. Wait, I might not be able to sing.
え、で、歌ったほうがいいんですよね。
Wait, I should sing, right?
これで終わりじゃない！これもう持ってる今！ありがとうございます、本当に！
This isn't the end! I'm holding it right now! Thank you so much, really!
ドラゴンクエスト、最高！
Dragon Quest is the best!
妖怪ウォッチ、最高！ソニック、最高！
Yo-Kai Watch is the best! Sonic is the best!
じゃあ、え、ちょっと歌えないかも。どうしよう。
Well, um, I might not be able to sing. What should I do?
壱弐参 飛んで 肆 戊神 doggy
One, two, three, soaring, four, Inugami doggy,
めちゅ ドープ な mc
Such a dope MC,
この エリア きって の
The best in this area,
かなり ハード
Pretty hard.
身 の 丈 通り イチコロ さ
Taking you down to size.
噛みついて くる 荒くれ も
Even roughnecks who try to bite,
皆 まとめて 仲間 へ と
I'll bring them all together as friends
アップデート
And update them.
ほら 尾っぽ 振っ てご機嫌 に
See, wagging my tail in high spirits,
rock the beat
調子 いいね i wanna swing
Looking good, I wanna swing.
猛獣 牧れ行く ストリート すら
Even running wild across the streets,
顔 パス
VIP pass!
east side から west side
From the East Side to the West Side,
まで 縄張り だから
It's all my turf.
無知 無知 イキリ
Ignorant little show-offs,
優しく ぶっ飛ばす
I'll gently blow you away.
let you know my rule
ねんねん ころね oh yeah! get out of my way
Sleep tight, Korone, oh yeah! Get out of my way!
clap your hands
oh yeah! 手練 な パーティー
A party of skilled pros,
hihi awoo yo お利口 に wag your tail
Be a good pup, wag your tail,
bow - wow - wow !
Bow-wow-wow!
louder than words
ありのまま さ
Just as I am,
ワンワンワン
Woof, woof, woof!
ダー ダーダー フル な この 生き様
Living this full life to the max,
掴んだら 離さない
Once I grab on, I won't let go,
one chance で 輝く
Shine on one chance!
i'm a 絶対的 霊験 あらたか doggy god
I'm the absolute, miraculous doggy god.
世界 中席巻 犬国 計画
Taking over the world with the dog country plan,
年がらす年中 えらく 精 出す
Working hard all year round.
マイメン アヌビス に フェンリル ケルベロス
My men, Anubis, Fenrir, and Cerberus,
クー ・ シー オールロス 壱アミーゴ
Cú Chulainn, Allros, my amigo.
頷く こと 間違いなし
No doubt about it, you'll agree,
半端な 仕上がり の 牙
Fangs that aren't half-finished,
キラキラ で ブリン ブリン
Shining and bling-bling,
my vibes
飛翔 し はたゆく 羽 犬 の よう さ
Soaring like a winged dog,
north side から south side まで 網羅 する 覇 栄
Ruling from north side to south side.
統治 統治 一気に
Ruling everything in one sweep,
風 の よう すっ飛ばす
Blowing past like the wind.
let you know my groove
ねんねん ころね oh yeah! get out of my way
Sleep tight, Korone, oh yeah! Get out of my way!
clap your hands
oh yeah! 手練 な パーティー
A party of skilled pros,
hihi awoo yo お利口 に wag your tail
Be a good pup, wag your tail,
bow - wow - wow !
Bow-wow-wow!
louder than words
ありのまま さ
Just as I am,
ワンワンワン
Woof, woof, woof!
ダー ダーダー フル な この 生き様
Living this full life to the max,
掴んだら 離さない
Once I grab on, I won't let go,
one chance で 輝く
Shine on one chance!
i'm a 絶対的 霊験 あらたか doggy god
I'm the absolute, miraculous doggy god.
alright 鎖 に 繋がれる なんて まっ平 ごめん 遊ばせ
No way I'll let myself be chained down!
awoo 遠吠え 一発 で 十戒 の 如く 森羅万象 が 道 開ける
A single howl parts all creation like the Ten Commandments!
glory to dog いかにも 常軌 逸した i'm so fly
Glory to dog, I'm so fly, defying all norms!
on & on . . . 一切合切 お任せ あれ
Leave everything completely to me.
doggy doggy god
匂犬 群吠 バイバイ ベイビー
Bye-bye, baby, to the pack of dogs!
doggy doggy god
当然 今日 も 疾風怒濤
Storming ahead like a tempest today too!
doggy doggy god
clap your hands , wag your tail , on & on . . .
Clap your hands, wag your tail, on & on...
bow - wow - wow !
Bow-wow-wow!
louder than words
ありのまま さ
Just as I am,
ワンワンワン
Woof, woof, woof!
ダー ダーダー フル な この 生き様
Living this full life to the max,
掴んだら 離さない
Once I grab on, I won't let go,
one chance で 輝く
Shine on one chance!
i'm a 絶対的 霊験 あらたか doggy god
I'm the absolute, miraculous doggy god.
壱弐参 飛んで 肆 戊神 doggy
One, two, three, soaring, four, Inugami doggy,
めちゅ ドープ な mc
Such a dope MC,
この エリア きって の
The best in this area,
かなり ハード
Pretty hard.
身 の 丈 通り イチコロ さ
Taking you down to size.
噛みついて くる 荒くれ も
Even roughnecks who try to bite,
皆 まとめて 仲間 へ と
I'll bring them all together as friends
アップデート
And update them.
ほら 尾っぽ 振っ てご機嫌 に rock the beat
See, wagging my tail in high spirits, rock the beat!
doggy doggy god's street
listen up yeah
壱弐参 飛んで 馳せ 戌神
One, two, three, leaping forth, Inugami,
doggy めちゃ ドープ な mc
Doggy, what a dope MC!
この エリア きって の かなり ハード
Quite hardcore in this area,
身 の 丈 通り イチコロ さ
Down to size, going down in one hit!
噛み付いて 来る 荒れ も 皆 まとめ て
Even the rough ones biting back,
仲間 へ と アップデート
we upgrade them all into our crew!
ほら 尻尾 振っ て ご機嫌 に rock the beat
Wag your tail and rock the beat happily!
調子 良い ね i wanna swing
Feeling great, I wanna swing!
猛獣 徘徊 する ストリート すら 顔 パス
Breezing right through streets where beasts roam!
east side から west side まで 縄張り だから
From east side to west side is our turf,
無知 無知 イキリ 優しく ぶっ飛ばす
Gently blowing away all the clueless show-offs!
let you know my rule ねんねん ころね
Let you know my rule, rock-a-bye Korone!
oh yeah ! get out of my way
Oh yeah! Get out of my way!
もしくは clap your hands
Or else, clap your hands!
手練 な パーティー
A skillful party,
お 利口 に wag your tail
act nice and wag your tail!
bow - wow - wow !
Bow-wow-wow!
遅れちゃったけど 3Dライブ、すごく楽しかったー！！
Though a bit late, the 3D live was so much fun!!
待っていてくれたみんな たくさん頑張ってくれた運営さん
To everyone who waited and management who worked so hard,
ありがとうございました！わっほー♡
thank you so much! Wahho♡
来年もまた、みんなとお祝いできますように…
May we celebrate together again next year...